<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://winnieyangwannan.github.io/RippleTagging/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://winnieyangwannan.github.io/RippleTagging/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-04-20T02:21:54+00:00</updated><id>https://winnieyangwannan.github.io/RippleTagging/feed.xml</id><title type="html">🧠🏷️ Selection of experience for memory by hippocampal sharp wave ripples</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">A short post regarding fig. 4G-H</title><link href="https://winnieyangwannan.github.io/RippleTagging/blog/2024/fig4H/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A short post regarding fig. 4G-H"/><published>2024-04-19T15:12:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-19T15:12:00+00:00</updated><id>https://winnieyangwannan.github.io/RippleTagging/blog/2024/fig4H</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://winnieyangwannan.github.io/RippleTagging/blog/2024/fig4H/"><![CDATA[<p>Since the publication of our paper, we have received many constructive feedbacks and questions. I decided to provide answers to some of the questions here so more people will be benefit from those important questions.</p> <p>Some people asked about fig. 4H in the original <a href="http://127.0.0.1:4000/RippleTagging/Paper/">paper</a>, in particular, what exactly is shown on the x and y axes?</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/RippleTagging/assets/img/QA/fig4_GH-480.webp 480w,/RippleTagging/assets/img/QA/fig4_GH-800.webp 800w,/RippleTagging/assets/img/QA/fig4_GH-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/RippleTagging/assets/img/QA/fig4_GH.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Fig.1 Panel G and H of fig.4 from our original paper. </div> <p>I have made a diagram to explain fig. 4G and 4H. There are two components:</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/RippleTagging/assets/img/QA/explaine_fig4_H-480.webp 480w,/RippleTagging/assets/img/QA/explaine_fig4_H-800.webp 800w,/RippleTagging/assets/img/QA/explaine_fig4_H-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/RippleTagging/assets/img/QA/explaine_fig4_H.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Fig.2 Diagram to explain results in fig.4G-H. Note, this figure is just to illustrate how we performed the analysis (not real data). </div> <ol> <li> <p>First, we plotted bar graphs for the distribution of replays across trial blocks (panel A and B in the diagram, corresponds to fig. 4G in the paper) for each individual recording session.</p> </li> <li> <p>Then, we build the scatter plot showing the correlation between maze and post-sleep replay patterns pooled from all data points in all sessions (panel C in the diagram, corresponds to fig. 4H in the paper). To further explain how those two components are related to each other:</p> </li> </ol> <ul> <li> <p>For each trial block in each example session, we took its replay proportion (#of replay in a particular trial block / total # of replay in that session) during maze as x-axis value and replay proportion during post-sleep as y-axis value of the summary scatter plot (panel C here and fig. 4H in the paper).</p> <ul> <li> <p>To give a concrete example, suppose the trial block 5-10 in example session 1 accounts for 100% of the maze replays in that session, and that same trial block also accounts for 100% of the post-sleep replays (panel A), then this data point would locate at the (1,1) coordinate of the summary plot in panel C.</p> </li> <li> <p>The example data point in panel B follows the same logic.</p> </li> </ul> </li> <li> <p>Note that proportion values (y-axis values in A and B) are normalized (scaled between 0 and 1) so that they can be compared across sessions.</p> </li> </ul> <hr/> <p>We had very limited space to explain all our interesting results in detail in the original paper. I hope the explanation here helps!</p> <p>Further feedbacks in general (including criticisms) are welcome! Feel free to leave a comment here or email us (winnieyangwn96@gmail.com, Gyorgy.Buzsaki@nyulangone.org).</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Q&amp;A"/><category term="Explanation"/><category term="Results"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Authors' notes on readers' questions regarding fig. 4H]]></summary></entry></feed>